Hello.
The next thing we're going to do is add some controls to our game.
For example, we'll make it to when the player presses spacebar.
They'll jump inside of our game in order to add controls and start that unreal engine, head over to
edit and go project settings.
And scroll down and go to input.
In Unreal Engine.
We can add controls in two ways.
You can either add the control as an action mapping or an axis mapping.
I'm going to go over what each of them do now.
So we just go to action mapping and click add new action mapping.
And here the budgets for this jump.
Then underneath here we can assign the key that we want to assign to this action.
So we look for space for.
So what this will mean is when I press the spacebar on inside of my game, it will call the jump action
mapping.
We can make it so that action mappings are configured to multiple buttons.
So just go here and go out and under here if I look for left control.
We've made it so that when I press spacebar or left control, it will call the jump action mapping inside
of my game.
Now, the way actual mappings work is we can tell whether a button is pressed or released.
So if my player is holding spacebar with an home, we have to tap when we are pressing the spacebar
and we'll be able to tell when we have let go of the spacebar with an axis mapping.
It will continuously read the input of a key word pressing.
So I'll showcase what I mean by this if I go add new axis mapping.
And let's just call this move, Right?
So when I want my player to move, right, I want them to press the right button on that keyboard.
So here, let's look for.
Right.
And as you can see, this has a value of one.
So if I press the right button on my keyboard, this will make this move right axis mapping have a value
of one.
If I just add another axis mapping to this group and make it left.
And I make the body of this minus one.
When I press the left button on my keyboard, it will make the move, right?
Have an X mapping value of minus one.
And we're basically going to use this exit mapping to make our placard to move towards the right when
they press the right button and move towards the left.
When they press the left one.
When we set up the input in our player character, you'll see much more clearly how this all works.
I just want to add another thing and make it so I press the button.
My player character will move towards the right and when I press the button.
My character will move towards the left.
So make sure that the left and a have a value of minus one and the right and have a value of one.
We can close this.
Now we set up the controls for our game.
The next thing we want to do is set up a2d character that we can play our games inside of our content
folder.
Let's create a new folder.
If we right click and go new folder and just call this player character.
Head inside this photo and just right click again and go to Blueprint class and go to all classes and
under search.
Look for paper seed.
I'm going to collect this one paper Z character.
And just call this our pleasure.
Underscore beep.
So inside of here, we're going to write all the information about how a player should behave and act
inside of our game.
So if we just double click and hit inside here.
The first thing we're going to do is go to our components tab and go to our Sprite here.
Under our Sprite, basically, let us know how our player is going to look inside of our game.
We're going to go to our details and then go to the Sprite panel.
And if you remember earlier, we made a bunch of flip books at the start.
I want us to look for the idle flipbook and just select it.
So we can currently see this looks quite small.
So we need to make it a bit bigger so it fits inside of this capsule.
So in order to do that, just select it.
And then under here, under scale, just make sure this little anchor is checked.
And if I just increase the size of one of the values here to something like three.
Because that ankle is checked, it will scale everything uniformly.
If I just let this unchecked, I can scale this, but everything's not going to scale uniformly.
So that's why I just leave it checked when I'm scaling things.
You can also scale things by just going here to the Select and scale object tool.
This will change the 3D gizmo.
And if I just let the middle one and make sure all the three ones are highlighted and just drag on my
mouse, they'll become a bit bigger.
So I'm just going to move my sprite so it fits inside my character's capsule.
If you're not happy with the capsule collision, you can just select it and we can adjust the value
of them by changing the capsule half height and the capsule radius.
For now, I'm just going to leave it as I think it looks kind of fun.
So this is our player character.
Right now, if I just imported them inside of our game, they wouldn't work.
And that's because we need to make sure that our player character has a camera.
So we just select our capsule component and go ahead and look for spring on.
This is what camera is going to be attached to.
We just want to set the spring on and rotate it so it's facing our player character.
Put the spring on selected.
Just go ahead and look for camera.
And just take this camera.
So it's single player character.
And but just like with spring gone, we can adjust the target element to make it closer or further away
from our planned character.
Next.
Before we add the controls to our black character, I just want them working inside of our level.
So if we just close this and head over to window.
And go to wild settings.
This will add this little tab here.
And here it's going to ask us for our game mode.
So a game basically tells the game what player character we should start our game as.
So we're going to create a new game mode.
So in order to do that, just right click Go Blueprint class and go game mode based.
And just pull this off to the game mode.
Head inside her.
And go to default pawn.
So our player BP is a blueprint.
A blueprint is any blueprint that can be possessed by our player character.
We just want to go to our default point class and select the player BP.
And just go compile and see.
And now here underworld settings.
I just drank my two day mood here.
When I start my game, I'm going to start as this player.
BP In order to determine where in our world our parents are, we can just go here to add quickly things
to the product and select basic and select player start.
So character is going to start here inside of our game.
And now I just go play.
McCain will note, and this will be where my character starts.
So nice.
Everything is working.
The next thing I do is add the controls that we set up earlier, so they work with our player character.